DIRECTOR

Summary

Seeking a leadership position at a growing company where I can use my skills and experience to lead change and growth. Passionate around release processes and incorporating devops fundamentals to improve flow of the value chain. 8+ years Software Quality Assurance for retail solutions. 10+ years in engineering leadership positions in retail technology Leader in organizational change management initiatives Highly motivated, self-disciplined, and dedicated to excellence. Goal-oriented and innovative problem solver, who enjoys a challenge. Excellent communication skills and enjoy dealing with customers. Promoted rapidly under multiple management teams and company owners Passionate technology leader always looking to push a DevOps culture and philosophy into areas not always considered part of the movement, Support for example..

Highlights

- DevOps
- Big Data
- Business Analytics
- Business Intelligence
- Client Relationship Management
- IT Strategy
- · Log Consolidation tools Sumo logic, ELK stack, manage engine suite
- Program/Project Management
- SDLC (Agile & RUP)
- Software Project Delivery
- Team Building
- Vendor Management
- Monitoring Tools New Relic, Solar Winds, Nagios, etc

Experience

03/2014 to Current

Director Cvs Health i¹/₄ Brentwood, TN

- Cardlytics is a leading advertising & Technology Company and the pioneer in Card-Linked Marketing.
- Through partnerships with nearly 400 financial institutions, including Bank of America, Lloyds Banking Group and others, the company has
 insight into consumer purchase behavior for ~70% of U.S.
- households and ~30% of U.K.
- households, capturing spending across all stores and categories.
- As Application Support Director I managed groups covering Production DBA, Hosting, Dev Ops, and Production Support.
- Databases currently in use are mostly MS SQL Server, with a few My SQL and Vertica clusters.
- Instituted a formal change management process to ease auditing and control of the production environments while at the same time increasing speed of deployment.
- Constructed a DevOps group to cover deployment and systems management to create a clear line of distinction between corporate IT and Application software.
- Created and eventually handed off a Maintenance development team to deal with defects in legacy products that are still actively used by the business Acted as lead for all SOX related activities within the Engineering team.
- Worked closely with legal, risk, and compliance In addition led an effort to build out a development maintenance team to focus on high priority production defects, team was handed over to fellow technical director once operational.
- Strong focus on tactical effectiveness to lead then way for strategic gains.

11/2011 to Current

Director Cvs Health i1/4 Bristol, VA

- Omnico Group was established to combine the software expertise of Clarity with the hardware of DigiPoS.
- As operations director I inherited all aspects of operations within the US operations including development, project mgmt., solution architects plus all of the responsibilities below.
- Currently manage 10 direct reports covering all operational areas of the business.
- Key member and contributor of the Executive team.
- Server as key escalation point for all issues both internally and externally with customers Leading a transition in the company to start a
 product model as well as services.
- Lead US team to win company contest for exceeding EBITDA goals for Q1 and Q2 this year.
- Led an effort to reduce costs through gaining efficiencies in roles and process.
- Leading a team on track to exceed budget and set record levels for EBITDA out of US office.

10/2010 to 10/2011

Manager Ricoh Americas Corporation i¹/₄ Richfield, OH

- ClarityLive Professional Services Clarity Commerce acquired MATRA systems to add to a set of products targeting the POS market globally.
- As the professional services manager at Clarity I inherited support and IT in addition to QA.
- In addition began sitting in on and contributing to operational meetings with the executive team.

- Established tracking metrics in the support group that led to a sharp decrease in customer reported incidents being open longer than 30 days.
- Improved supports ability to meet or exceed SLA's for high severity issues, queue shrank from 100+ to less than 10 on most days.
- Began blurring the responsibilities of QA, Support, and IT such that efficiencies could be gained in a larger cross functional team.
- Responsibilities remained separate but cross training was critical.
- Shifted responsibilities from support to IT to maintain labs and hardware which grew our IT department and allowed that group to generate revenue without increasing staff.
- Successfully developed folks for career advancement both internally and externally.
- Led a very aggressive effort to promote folks with product knowledge to more substantial revenue generating roles.

09/2008 to 10/2010

Quality Assurance Manager Peraton i1/4 Westfield, VA

- MATRA is a retail solutions and services provider with offices around the world.
- MATRA has developed Point Of Sale solutions and services for major retailers since 1991, and is one of the most innovative suppliers of retail technology in the world today.
- Responsible for scheduling and managing the operations of QA within the delivery team at MATRA.
- Responsible for estimating QA effort on projects and tracking variance.
- Ensure that organizational quality standards are in place and adhered to.
- This encompassed many things with a focus on the testing and defect management within the delivery team.
- Responsible for overall quality of the product that is delivered to customer.
- Lead an effort to get QA involved in customer acceptance testing Lead an effort to get MATRA to own customer configuration for new customers.
- Managed this process for a new customer from start to production which resulted in decreased QA time.
- Utilizing my advanced SQL skills to increase maintainability.
- Implemented a formal testing process that mapped responsibilities from requirements gathering to customer pilot.
- Assisted in major organizational changes to improve efficiency and quality.

02/2005 to 09/2008

Quality Assurance Engineer Booz Allen Hamilton Inc. i1/4 Fort Belvoir, VA

- MATRA is a retail solutions and services provider with offices around the world.
- MATRA has developed Point Of Sale solutions and services for major retailers since 1991, and is one of the most innovative suppliers of
 retail technology in the world today.
- Analyzed system requirements, functional specifications, and other technical documentation in order to prepare test plans and author detailed test cases.
- Identified aspects of the functionality that were not clear and could eventually result in incorrect implementation of the function.
- Generated and maintained test data to be used during all phases of testing.
- Executed tests and provided feedback early in the SDLC Defects were reported through proprietary system.
- Created an automated testing framework using SILK Test to increase testing effectiveness and speed.
- The results I achieved during my own time were used to convince upper management that automation was viable with our product and had tremendous ROI.
- As the lone automation engineer I created several hundred tests that executed on a nightly basis with results waiting for review each morning.
- Hired and trained someone that was to be dedicated to automation script creation while I provided architecture and guidance as needed.
- The number of test cases is growing and allowing us to find issues quicker.
- At this point my peers at MATRA were convinced that automation would work with our products when it was previously thought to be too
 difficult.
- Responsible for maintaining the QA lab and its entire configuration.
- In addition a new dedicated lab for automation was put in place after results of testing continued to impress.

04/2003 to 02/2005

Product Selection Specialist XTRAS INC i1/4 City, STATE

- Xtras, Inc is a small software reseller located in Atlanta.
- As a small business it is no coincidence that I performed many tasks in my daily routine.
- I started as simply a call center rep and quickly progressed to begin handling the following duties.
- Handled customer service issues both technical and non-technical.
- Managed vendor logistics and relationships.
- Maintained information on websites that pertained to products and vendors.
- Performed all purchasing and Inventory management responsibilities.
- Developed relationships with customers by following up with them after sales.
- Wrote SQL queries to access back end data Created ASP pages and SQL stored procedures to increase productivity in my daily duties.

Education

August 2001

 $B.B.A: Computer\ (Management)\ Information\ Systems\ GEORGIA\ STATE\ UNIVERSITY\ i'\ Lity\ ,\ State\ Computer\ (Management)\ Information\ Systems\ GEORGIA\ STATE\ UNIVERSITY\ i'\ Lity\ ,\ State\ Computer\ (Management)\ Information\ Systems\ GEORGIA\ STATE\ UNIVERSITY\ i'\ Lity\ ,\ State\ Computer\ (Management)\ Information\ Systems\ GEORGIA\ STATE\ UNIVERSITY\ i'\ Lity\ ,\ State\ Computer\ (Management)\ Information\ Systems\ GEORGIA\ STATE\ UNIVERSITY\ i'\ Lity\ ,\ State\ Computer\ (Management)\ Information\ Systems\ GEORGIA\ STATE\ UNIVERSITY\ i'\ Lity\ ,\ State\ Computer\ (Management)\ Information\ Systems\ GEORGIA\ STATE\ UNIVERSITY\ i'\ Lity\ ,\ State\ Computer\ (Management)\ Information\ Systems\ GEORGIA\ STATE\ UNIVERSITY\ i'\ Lity\ ,\ State\ Computer\ (Management)\ Information\ Systems\ GEORGIA\ STATE\ UNIVERSITY\ i'\ Lity\ ,\ State\ Computer\ (Management)\ Information\ Systems\ GEORGIA\ STATE\ UNIVERSITY\ i'\ Lity\ ,\ State\ Computer\ (Management)\ Information\ Systems\ GEORGIA\ STATE\ UNIVERSITY\ i'\ Lity\ ,\ UNIVERSITY\ I'\ Lity\ ,\ UNIVERSITY\ I'\ Lity\ ,\ UNIVERSITY\ I'\ Lity\ I'\ Lity\ ,\ UNIVERSITY\ I'\ Lity\ I'\ Lity\$

Systems

Skills

advertising, Agile, ASP, auditing, automation, Banking, Big Data, budget, Business Intelligence, call center, change management, hardware, Client, customer service, DBA, Databases, Delivery, engineer I, estimating, financial, focus, functional, Inventory management, IT Strategy, Team Building, legal, logic, logistics, Director I, director, managing, market, Marketing, meetings, access, office, win, My SQL, organizational, POS, Project Management, project mgmt, purchasing, quality, QA, Relationship Management, requirements gathering, retail, RUP, sales, scheduling, SDLC, script, SILK, SLA, MS SQL Server, SQL, strategic, systems management, technical documentation, Vendor Management, websites, author